This is quicksort in plain Haskell,
sorting the list [3, 1, 2].
MicroHs (a tiny Haskell compiler) turns it into
combinators: no variables, just tree-rewriting.
Start with the classic core:
the combinators S and K.
K x y = x.
(Keep the first argument, drop the second.)
S x y z = x z (y z).
(Copy z into both branches, then apply.)
S and K alone are Turing-complete:
enough to express any computation.
MicroHs compiles to a richer set: supercombinators.
The rules firing up top, like P, O, J and Y,
are those supercombinators.
Each one still reduces to S and K underneath.
There is an even smaller basis:
a single combinator, ι (iota).
ι = λx. x S K.
Applied to itself, ι ι = I, the identity.
K = ι(ι(ιι)),    S = ι(ι(ι(ιι))).
So S, K, and every supercombinator collapse to ι.
Each step rewrites a combinator,
but every frame is drawn as pure ι.
In the picture, each dot is one ι,
and each branch is an application.
A term is one bit-code:  iota = 0 | 1 iota iota
(0 is ι; 1 applies the next two).
This whole turning mandala is one closed ι-term.
Data is compiled too: each constructor
becomes a function that picks a branch.
Numbers are Peano: a zero,
and the successor (Succ) of a smaller number.
Zero picks the zero branch;
Succ n picks the other, carrying n.
Lists and booleans work the same way,
each compiling to its own combinator.
So this tree is quicksort [3, 1, 2]:
data and code, all of it in ι.
Listen: each combinator family has its own note,
and recursion drops to a low bass.
The algorithm: pick a pivot, split the rest
into ≤ and >, sort each side, join.
That ≤ comparison is the phrase you keep hearing.
The recursion is the Y combinator (Y f → f (Y f)):
each call copies the sorter and expands the tree.
Comparison by comparison,
it reaches the sorted answer: [1, 2, 3].
And to read a list back, we un-cons it:
peel off the head, then the rest.
1, 2, 3.  Sorted, in pure ι.